Commanders family, welcome in a free
agency Fridays. We are here in the Big
Bear AI Command Center studio for a
special version of next man up because
we got one of our new linebackers in the
building. Leo Chanel just pulled up,
just put pen to paper. You got your bag,
man. How you feeling? I'm feeling great.
Being here already, man, I feel the
energy, the love of the game just like
it's seeping through.
You know, every everybody staff top to
bottom, few players walking everybody's
just like ready to go, man. The culture
is is awesome and welcoming here.
Congratulations, man. We're so happy to
have you be here and you were a highly
sought after free agent. What makes you
say you're I'm going to leave the
Chiefs? You've been there for your whole
career. What makes you say you want to
come in? Yeah, I mean, not going to lie,
it was tough. You know, that was that
was my team. I never really saw myself
leaving there and, you know, just became
a reality and, you know, you guys came
came over and just talking with coach
Quinn, coach Jones and
just hearing so much about them and what
they bring to the table, hearing that
all the guys love them.
You know, even peers to them, everybody
has just so much respect for them and
just knowing the players, the guys they
got on this team already and
we didn't meet expectations last year
here, but, you know, I just know the
culture, the guys that we have in this
building, guys we're bringing in.
We got some dudes who are making making
runs in free agency like, you name it.
We're about to be have a great draft,
you know it.
So, I'm just excited to be part of it.
I'm loving that we. We we we. I love it
all of that stuff, man. And this was we
talked about it before we started
recording. This is your first free
agency period where you've got to be
sought after, where you had to go
through this. What was it like, man?
Because I understand that that could be
a little stressful.
Yeah, I mean, it's different. You know,
draft is like, okay, you're going here
whether you like it or not and now it's,
you know, I got some options. I get to
choose, you know, what best fits me and
I got to look for my family, look out
for my family as well, my girls. So,
it's cool being able to, okay, like what
do I like? What culture, you know, fits
me best? What what way will they utilize
me?
You know, how are the you know, the
coaches whatever it is, you know, I can
I can specifically point that out and
and and choose for myself and you know,
again, it was it was kind of an easy
decision, you know, being here,
ready to raise hell. So,
ready to go. [laughter] We love that,
man. When you talk about those
conversations you did have, and they're
talking about how they're going to use
you and utilize you, what were some of
those conversations like? It's just, you
know, having having that experience, you
know, in in KC and Wisconsin whether I
can be in the middle of the field off
the ball, a weakside linebacker, whether
I need to be on the ball, you know,
addressing the tackle, whatever it is.
You know, I can do it. You know, and and
they were very encouraging and welcoming
in that fact and that's kind of what
made made it very attractive.
Just the way they were excited to, you
know, take advantage of my skill set,
you know, my athleticism and
just really looking forward to it.
>> And that versatility is shown on the
film, right? You've been all over the
field. Where are you most comfortable
at? You know, I I have definitely most
reps, you know, off the ball and I want
to continue to grow on the ball if I can
as a pass rusher.
You know, it's great learning from guys
Chris Jones, George Karlaftis, Charles
Charles we got Charles Menahu Chuck,
you know, over here. So, they were great
mentors to me.
You know, they love the game and so I
want to keep building especially on the
ball pass rush.
You know, cuz I've done, you know,
middle of the field off the ball, you
know, rushing on guards, rushing on
running backs and that's where I
definitely excel. So, it's continue to
build that and continue to make plays in
the in the pass game as well. And you
really fit the bill for what we've heard
from our new defensive coordinator
Dorante Jones on what he wants. He wants
versatility. He wanted us to get
younger. He wanted us to get faster and
you showed that athleticism on tape
years ago. Let's check it out real
quick.
>> Oh, here we go. Look at that man right
there. Now, I looked it up, my brother.
15 ft on average. That's how big a
double decker bus is on average, 15 ft.
And you just jump up there and you climb
up there and get this had Commanders
fans so excited that they had a freak
athlete that was capable of just pulling
up something like this. What's going on
in this video, man?
>> What's going on? If you really want to
know, [laughter]
it's a parade. So, it's you know, a
little something in the system, to be
honest with you.
>> [laughter]
>> You know, I was just hyped up. You know,
you win something like that, you get
excited. And to be honest, actually,
like my wife, you know, she was pregnant
at the time. She was up there. You know,
she's getting like champagne sprayed in
her face and I'm like, oh shoot, I'm out
in the street. I got my wife up here
still. So,
I remembered her. So, I'm like, oh
shoot, what's the fastest way to get
down this bus? I'm like, [laughter] I I
got to try to jump, you know. Like the
bus I think was the bus moving? Maybe?
It looked like it it looked like it
might have had a little bit of Okay, it
was still. It was still.
>> Okay, so I was I was being a little
safe, you know. Still impressive. Yeah,
so. No, I I had to get up there quick,
you know. A hormonal wife is
>> [laughter]
>> I understand. I got to get in trouble. I
got to I'm going to get on this bus
right now. How did you end up off the
bus? Why weren't you on the bus to begin
with? You go down, you know, they they
have you go down if you want to be up
there, you know, you got cigars and, you
know, wherever you want to hang out with
your family up top. But if you want to
be crazy like Willie Gay, you know, he's
Willie Gay all-time teammate Willie Gay.
He's awesome.
>> [laughter]
>> He was on the street, you know,
high-fiving fans. Such such a cool thing
to be part of. We'll experience that
that shortly, I hope. Oh, yeah. And, you
know, just just a lot of stuff going
through. Adrenaline, you name it. Now,
we normally don't show videos on next
man up, but to me when I watch that,
that shows why Commanders fans are so
excited to have you. That's an athletic
freak right there. That's a bad man.
Believe it or not, that is an athletic
freak and that's what we have seen on
the film. When you talk to Dorante
Jones, our new defensive coordinator,
how excited are you to play for a guy
like that that knows how to utilize
somebody with all your different skill
sets? Oh, former former Wisconsin
Badger. That's that's that's the biggest
part right there. But no, I mean, you
know, what he brought to the table, you
know, what utilized, you know,
Minnesota, whatever it is, like he knew
how to get guys involved. You know, a
lot of times, you know, you get you get
defensive line, you know, eating and,
you know, enjoying the
benefit. They work really hard, you
know, you got to have that and so it's
it's cool also, you know, have
linebackers involved, too. You know, and
not speak not speaking ill of anywhere
else and they do great job at KC, but,
you know, just speaking to me
personally, what I what I can bring to
the table, you know, individually
to be able to help this team out is is
pretty cool just hearing it. At this
point in your career, do you feel like
you've been underutilized a little bit?
You know, it's it happens, you know. I
love, you know, everything we had going
on in KC and
it just happens, you know, with the
business and,
you know, whatever it is, but I feel
like I can be utilized definitely more
now and be able to have that [snorts]
role,
you know, whatever whatever the reason
may be. Like I'm just excited to be part
of it.
>> Yeah, do you have like that hunger to be
that every down linebacker? Like I mean,
I got to imagine so, right?
>> Yeah, I mean, that's that's what made it
a lot easier, you know, leaving there,
coming here. Just speaking the
opportunity,
what I can do, what I can bring to the
table, be on be on the field
as much as I want to and as much as I
can with whatever the coaches want ask
of me.
So, I'm just I'm really excited for the
opportunity. And then we watched that
video and of course you're celebrating a
Super Bowl. You got two of them things,
man, and I know that that is the Mecca
of all things, right? Getting that Super
Bowl. How can you help take what you've
learned from those Super Bowl
appearances, what you've learned from
playing in those Super Bowl locker
rooms? How can you take that here and
help these young guys out? Yeah, I'm
used to, you know, we have a long season
already, but I'm used to, you know,
going late into February, having the
first game of the season. So, I'm I'm
used to those things. I'm used to being
in the big moments, the most
high-stakes, high-pressure situations
and knowing how to be level-headed. You
know, sometimes it's everybody loves the
game of football. Everybody's juiced up,
ready to play. They want to hit
somebody. They want to catch a ball in
the end zone.
But the biggest guys know how to balance
it, you know, and balance the the focus
and the energy. So, I think just having
that experience going to three Super
Bowls
really helped me have that that balance
cuz, you know, like I said, it's easy to
get get revved up in the in those
situations. So,
I could bring that experience as well,
you know, cuz playoff football Super
Bowl
Super Bowl football is a lot different
than regular season games. So, I'm
ready, you know, with that experience.
And it takes a certain type of team,
right? It takes a certain type of locker
room. A lot of things have to go right
to win a Super Bowl. When you look at
what we have here currently, right?
There's a lot of new faces including
you. But when you look at what we have
here currently with the Commanders, do
you see
Super Bowl hopes there?
>> really do. You know, just the culture
alone, you know, that's that's a big
thing. Like you look around like, how
are the guys responding to things? How
are how are guys walking in the locker
room like every single day and
it makes it makes a big difference, you
know, and uh just seeing these guys
already, you know, they they got it. You
know, I can see it, you know, in the
coaches' eyes, you know, the players
that I met so far in their eyes,
their excitement, the way they talk.
You know, they were you know, they I've
seen like how they play on film.
Obviously, again, we didn't meet
expectations last year, but I know that
we're capable of it, you know, what
they've showed you know, before that and
you know, what these players are capable
of, the guys they're bringing in, like
the you know, those dudes, man, they're
ballers we're bringing in. Like I said,
we're going to have a great draft. We're
going to have the team, the players to
do it. We're going to have the energy,
the culture, like you name it. It's it's
just up to us how we utilize it. Talk
about those guys they're bringing in.
There's another Chief coming in the
building, man. How was it? How was it?
Have you guys had those conversations
knowing that you guys will both be here?
>> Yeah, as soon as soon as I saw the the
notification, you know, he's coming. I'm
like, I I reached out to him. I'm like,
dude, let's go. Like that's the best
feeling, you know, just got you to
coming in coming in together and, you
know, I love Chuck. You know, he's a
great dude. He's hungry, like hungrier
than anybody.
You know, you can put him up there and
he's he's been with the systems. I know
how to get to the ball. He's been with
San Fran, whatever and
he he just knows. He's a great vet with
great knowledge and I'm joining up with
Allegretti, Wylie as well and a coach
Jones, a little Wisconsin connection.
So, it's nice having that familiarity,
too, and and also look forward to
building new relationships. Leo, welcome
home, man. And finally, in closing, man,
the fans are so excited to hear from
you. That's your ISO cam right there,
man. Can you just give the fans a
message on what to expect from Leo
Chanel now that he's in the building?
>> Yeah, you know, I'm ready to just bring
violence, physicality. I've mentioned it
before. That's that's just who I am. You
know, I I want to be able to get
downhill. I want to be able to hit
somebody.
Get guys going on the sidelines,
whatever it is, whatever situation, you
know, I'm going to have that positivity,
that energy ready ready go get things
rolling. Hey, man, he is not lying. I
was tired. Now I'm wide awake, man.
Leo brought in the energy. Brother, we
appreciate you, man. And again,
congratulations. Nothing promised in the
NFL. You earned this, and we're so happy
to have you here, man. Thank you so
much. Commanders family on next man up,
part of free agency Fridays. Leo Chenal
is in the building, and hopefully we'll
have him climbing some Super Bowl double
deckers pretty soon, man.
Appreciate you, dog.
>> [laughter]